because of your policy I
из-за политики вашей Я
think You know what's most interesting when
думаю Знаешь что самое интересное когда
some Russians, here are the Russians Yes, from
какие-то российские вот русские Да из
Moscow or St. Petersburg they say but when
там Москвы Питера говорят но когда вот
you, Teleut, yes you understand that you were
ты телеут да ты понимаешь что тебя
captured and exterminated, you have
захватили истребили у вас осталось блин
2,000 people left, damn, yes you are forgetting your language,
2.000 человек да вы забываете свой язык
you have no prospects for
у вас нет никаких ни перспектив до
your people Yes and you say
вашего народа Да и ты рассказываешь у
you have some kind of policy there, that's why we
вас там какая-то политика поэтому мы
attacked
напали
Hello, Great, I'm from the city of
Здравствуйте Здорово Я из города
Khmelnitsk, where are you
Хмельницке Вы
from? Scuba
откуда я Скуба
Kemerovo Yes, I understand And you are a Kazakh Shore, who are
Кемерова Да понял А ты казах шорец кто
you? Kiut Kilit, I wonder what kind of
ты киут килит интересно а что это за
Kilit is this, is it somewhere among the northern peoples
килит это где-то из северных народов
Yes, these are the small peoples of Siberia,
Да нет это малочисленные народы Сибири
and the Teleut, not Keu And
а телеу не Кеу А
those are interesting, yes there are 2,000 people, like Yes, from the
те интересно да 2000 людей типа есть Да
Kemerovo region, yes It's interesting, yes I didn't
Кемеровской области да Интересно да не
know, I didn't know You are the Turkic peoples Yes, the
знал не знал это вы тюркские народы Да
indigenous Jurassic
Юрский коренной
people You are related, the
Народ у вас получается родственные это
Altai Shors, yes, it's
алтайцы шорцы да
interesting, yes I didn't know, because the Shors, knowing, did
да Интересно да не знал пото шорцев знав
n't know, it's cool I'll read it later, it's very
не знал прикольно почитаю потом очень
interesting because I  that's when I
интересно да потому что я вот когда
meet people from Kuzbass yes Usually
людей встречаю из Кузбасса да Обычно
Russians Yes I'm telling you Yes what is this
русских Да я вот рассказываю Да что это
uh the territories of the Turkic peoples were
ж ээ территории тюркских народов были
there the Turkic peoples lived There they are like no what are
там жили тюркские народы Там они такие
you telling there we are like
не не что ты рассказываешь там мы как
Russians there have lived there since time immemorial yes
русские там из покон веков там жили да
they specially try
они специально стараются историю ээ там
not to touch the history uh what happened 200-300 years ago Yes so as
что было 200-300 лет назад не трогать Да
not to say who is indigenous here
ээ не говорить кто тут коренной на этих
No well I'm also kidding I say
Нет ну я я также прикалываюсь Я говорю
you lived under the barbecue for 300 years Tatars There
вы 300 лет под мангало татарами жили Там
and so on so I'm kidding Well I understand and
и так далее так прикалываюсь Ну понял а
what are you communicating here
чём тут общаетесь
[music]
[музыка]
Yes it's just interesting the
Да так просто интересно настроение
general mood to see I have what I I I'm
общее посмотреть у меня то что мне мне
interested in what the difference is on TV
мне интересно что разница по телевизору
and the difference I understood from people But
говорят и разница вот от людей понял А
look at
вот смотри
you like Which people are closer in spirit
тебе как бы Какой народ ближе по духу
Kazakhs or
казахи или
Russians to me no which one is mine Teleut
русские мне не какой мне свой телеутский
yes yes Well for example which people do you
да да Ну вот например какой ты более
consider more related Kazakh
родственным считаешь народом казахский
or
или
Russian Teleut
русский телеутский
except Teletskoye here Brotherly people what is
кроме телецкого вот Братский народ какой
Teleut for you for Teleuts yes for
тебя телеутский для телеутов да для
Teleuts are a brotherly people what
телеутов братским народом какие есть
nations there are I don't meddle anywhere and I
народы никуда не лезу и никому ничего
don't give preference to anyone I just for
предпочтения не отдаю мне просто для
myself as an intelligent person who has a
себя как человеку умному
higher
который с высшим
education with a head for everything I'm just
образованием с головой всё мне просто
interested in listening to that you know your native
интересно послушать то то вы свой родной
language Teleut and so on yes yes
язык телеутский знаете так далее да да
it's similar to Kazakh Well it seems like you
он на казахский
understand the Kazakh language
похож Ну похо казахский язык понимаете
without a translator it turns out
без переводчика так получается
No not all well as the general meaning
Нет не весь ну как бы общий смысл у нас
in any case we differ from the Kazakhs I
в любом случае с казахами различается я
served in the army with the Kazakhs we have
в армии служил с казахами у нас
different languages ​​Well it's clear Because just
отличаются языки Ну ясно Потому что так
like we have, for example, Slavic languages
же как у нас например славянские языки
there Ukrainian Polish Ukrainian
там украинский польский украинский
Czech differs but still there are
чешский отличается но всё равно есть
a lot of common words Yes yes
очень много общих слов Да да
yes there are three you will have Uch like too yes
да там три у вас будет Уч типа тоже да
probably uto
наверно уто
Uch will be well well you see Yes as in all
Уч будет ну ну видишь Да как во всех
Turkic languages ​​Yes I understand Well do you have
тюркских языках Да понял Ну у вас
any questions
какие-то вопросы
in the sense Well there is some interesting
есть в смысле Ну какой-то интересный
question for me
вопрос ко мне
So I don't understand who you are a
есть Так я не понимаю кто вы
deputy Yes
депутат Да
seriously Ukrainian deputy Yes
серьёзно украинский депутат Да
Ukrainian deputy of the Gradsky city
украинский депутат Градского городского
council of the Khmelnytsky region m
совета Хмельницкой области м
Yes in general I have questions for you and
Да в целом У меня к вам вопросов то и
no I
нет мне
just have one question you have a terrible attitude towards all Russian
простом один вопрос Вы ко всему русскому
people as towards
народу прям ужасно относитесь как по к
Russian or Russian You are not
русскому или к российскому Ты же не
Russian for example you are Russian Well yes
русский например ты россиянин Ну да
I am not Russian
я я не русский
but
но
towards all Russians you have such a
всем ко всем россиянам у вас такое
terrible attitude oh no no no everyone all kick out of
ужасное о не не не всех всех выгнать из
Ukraine at
Украины по крайней
least Well that is and in fact towards me it is the
мере Ну то есть и по сути ко мне такое
same terrible Well not while you are sitting in
же ужасное Ну не пока вы сидите в
Kemerovo then so-so But if you were
Кемерово то так себе А вот если вы были
in Ukraine they really kicked you out there they
в Украине реально выгоняли вас там
screwed you And so
кидали И так
on But why did your country come to
дальше А вот зачем ваша страна пришла
kill people in my
убивать людей в моей
country well because of your politics I
стране ну изза полити ваши Я
think You know what is most interesting when
думаю Знаешь что самое интересное когда
some Russians Yes from
какие-то российские вот русские Да из
Moscow St. Petersburg they say but when
там Москвы Питера говорят но когда вот
you are a Teleut yes you understand that you were
ты телеут да ты понимаешь что тебя
captured exterminated you have
захватили истребили у вас осталось блин
2,000 people left damn yes you are forgetting your language
2.000 человек да вы забываете свой язык
you have no prospects before
у вас нет никаких ни перспектив до
your people Yes and you are telling me
вашего народа Да и ты рассказываешь у
you have some kind of policy there that is why we
вас там какая-то политика поэтому мы
attacked
напали
You understand look you have 2,000
Вот ты понимаешь ва смотри у вас 2000
Teleuts yes when will they send you away  to
есть телеутов да когда тебя отправят на
war in Ukraine Yes, 1999
войну в Украину Да останется 1999
Teleuts will remain Yeah,
телеутов
I'll
Угу я
go I
пойду я же
see 1999 Lyuts will remain Well, it turns out that
вижу останется 1999 лютов Ну получается
I'll go
так я пойду
Yes, when my country asks me I'll
Да когда меня страна моя попросит я
go ask say What's your name My name is
пойду попросит говори
Andrey What's your name
Как тебя зовут Меня Андрей Тебя как
My name is Misha Misha Yes, Misha, yes, the original aunt's name is Misha yes, the
зовут Меня Миша Миша Да вот Миша да
country will say
исконно тетское имя Миша да страна
look Son Misha Yes, my
скажет смотри Сынок Миша Да мо моя
original calf my my MKA And why are you
искона телиця мй мй й МКА А что Мишей
called Misha
называешься
then And what did you write down
тогда А что записали
Misha because according to the passport it's Misha Yeah
Миша потому что по паспорту Миша Ага
Pony were they embarrassed to write down the national name yes,
Поня стеснялись национальное имя
no, no, no one was
записать да нет нет никто никого не
embarrassed because there are laws that
стеснялся потому что есть законы которым
we obey and I grew up And what according to the
мы подчиняемся и я вырос А что по по
law you can't
закону нельзя имям Кай
write down the name Kai because my parents
написать потому что у меня родители так
thought it was necessary and I understood everything Look, in
посчитали нужным и тебя понял всё Смотри
short, the Motherland is telling you Misha we
короче Родина тебе говорит Миша мы тебе
couldn't give you affordable dentistry Yes,
не смогли дать доступную стоматологию Да
but we're giving you a ticket Russia
но мы тебе даём путёвку мне Россия
allowed me all the dentistry everything
позволила всю стоматологию всё
Come on, say it again, just don't burn
Давай ещё раз это скажи только не зажи
tell me just not for laugh tell me Russia
скажи только не за сме скажи Россия мне
for me everything is available everything allowed
по Россия всё доступное всё позволила
exactly for me Russia allowed
именно сжи мне Россия позволила
affordable
доступную
dentistry for me Russia allowed
стоматологию мне Россия позволила
affordable dentistry you somehow you are
доступную стоматологию ты как-то ты ты
embarrassed to speak here I speak loudly
стесняешься говорить вот Я громко говорю
here with I open to me Russia
вот с открываю мне Россия
about dentistry just thunder
про стоматологию просто гром
re My country allowed everything you for your
ре Моя страна всё позволила ты за свою
country look what a
страну смотри
smile Tell me Russia
улыбкой Скажи мне Россия
allowed szl What is there with you calmed down Us
позволила слы Что там у тебя успокоился
it's just a bomb in short yes for me Russia
Ус это просто бомба короче да мне Россия
allowed affordable
позволила доступную
dentistry Hello Hello I am
стоматологию Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я
from the city of Khmelnitsky Where are you from
из города Хмельницкий Вы откуда
And I am from Italy the city of Vila Franco And where did you
А я из Италии город Вила Франко А откуда
get there in
попали туда в
Italy I moved from Russia political
Италии Я с России переехал полит
emigrant
эмигрант
understood about the World Cup in general I
понял о ЧМ вообще
can
по разном могу
talk about different things yes anything By the way I am
поговорить да чём угодно Я кстати вас
watching you subscribed to you I understand now
смотрю подписан на вас понял теперь
somehow it is clear there join the
понятно как-то там присоединяйтесь к
fight
борьбе
And can I say it like that I let's say I have a
А можно и так сказать я скажем так имею
relation to the Finno-Mountain peoples and how
отношение к фино горски народам и как
specifically on
конкретно
my mother's side I am Komi And on my father's side I am Karelian
у меня по маме Коми А по отцу карела
Cool And how did they meet these are from
Прикольно А как они познакомились это с
different
разной
territories I was born in Siberia in general and there
территории Я в общем родился в Сибири и
were political repressions in the thirties-
были политические репрессии в тридцатые
forties  Soslana was ko interest
сороковые годы Сослана была ко интерес
Everything is
Всё
correct that is, it turns out somewhere grandparents
верно то есть получается где-то бабушки
were exiled somewhere then already Yes there
дедушки где-то были сосланы потом уже Да
even there even sla founded the
там даже там даже сла основали
corresponding ite here I studied their history
соответствую ите вот Я изучал их историю
then met people who are
потом познакомился с людьми которые
engaged in activism And in general, you can
занимаются активизм И в общем можно
say 2016 I am in this topic
сказать 2016 года я в этой теме
studying the culture of the language Well and
занимаюсь изучением культуры языка Ну и
so on and in 2022 an
так далее и в 2022 году
event happened that forced
э случилось событие которое заставило
me to emigrate And look, did you
меня эмигрировать А смотри а ты язык
study the Komi language like or Korela I generally
Коми типа или корельский изучал Я вообще
started with Finnish because it is close well yes yes yes
начал с Финского потому что близкий ну
and later I want to
дада да а впоследствии Я хочу и Коми
study Komi too Well yes Finnish is easier because there is a
изучить А ну да финский проще потому что
base for studying like well and with
есть и база для изучения как бы ну и с
whom to talk Yes interesting here Yes I got it
кем разговаривать Да интересно вот Да
right But uh I see there is a
всё верно понял А вот ээ я смотрю там
monitor There are different groups there Urals ska
монитор Разные группы есть там урали ска
And so on Well in Telegram uh and del
И так дальше Ну в телеграме э и дель
Ural too Well a bunch of all sorts of movements in our
Урал тоже Ну куча всяких движений у нас
Ukraine little is known about these all sorts of
в Украине мало знают по вот этих всяких
national I call them
национальных я их называю
national liberation movements Well
национально-освободительные движения Ну
so far most of them are
пока большинство из них
national-cultural Yes but they are
национально-культурные Да но они ж очень
transforming very quickly The point is  that in the
быстро трансформируются Дело в том что в
Soviet Union, just the same
При Советском Союзе как раз вот тех же
Karelians were driven out to Siberia Yes, the Komita and
карелов в Сибирь выгоняли Да комита и
how they did the powder, mixed the
как делали присыпке перемешивали народы
indigenous peoples, took them from their places And there are
коренные народы забирали С ихних мест А
very few Karelians there Yes, that's the problem,
карела очень мало Да вот в чём проблема
moreover, in Karelia now the Karelian
более того в Карелии сейчас Карельский
language has no official status
язык не имеет официального статуса
at all, it is the only republic in
никакого это единственная республика в
Russia where there is no official status for a
России которой Нет официального статуса
language, it's
языка это
terrible I understood how, for example, you
ужасно понял как как вот например ты
see Here is your movement, let's say Well, not
видишь Вот ваше движение скажем Ну не
only specifically there, Karelians or Komi, over the
только конкретно там карелов или Коми за
past 5 years, it has been increasing,
последние там 5 лет оно увеличивается
people are
людьми
interested in this, whether they are young or not,
интересуется об этом там молод или нет
more Well, I'll say So first, Oh, damn, an
более Ну я скажу Так что сначала Ай блин
interesting conversationalist broke off
оборвался интересный собеседник
Hello Hello, I am from the city of
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsky, where are you
Хмельницкий Вы
from? I am from the city of Almaty Kazakhstan
откуда Я из города Алматы Казахстан
Kazakhstan Russian Kazakh Pole
Казахстан русский казах поляк
Ukrainian what nation do you not know Uyghur
украинец какую нацию не знаешь Уйгур
Uyghur I know in the
уйгу знаю
Uyghur Autonomous Okrug, like they are
уйгурском автономном округе типа они
Turks But in short, it
тюрки Но короче оккупированные Китаем
turns out that they are occupied by China now yes yes yes nothing I didn't
получается сейчас да да да ниче се Не
expect Well, the Uyghurs are like a fairly ancient
ожидал Ну уйгуры типа довольно древний
people, the Uyghurs had writing when
народ письменность у уйгуров была когда
Moscow did not yet exist and in the Mongolian
ещё Москвы не было и в монгольской
empires writing in Uyghur
империи письменность же на уйгурском
was because the Uyghur intelligentsia
было потому что уйгурская интеллигенция
essentially played the role of a kind of
она по сути исполняла роль как
educated class
бы образованного сословия
there is true is true and you uh Your parents it
там правда правда а ты э Твои родители
turns out when they got to Oh
получается когда попали в
no my even my grandparents
О нет мои даже мои бабушки и дедушки уже
were already in Kazakhstan Well in what years in
были в Казахстане Ну в каких годах в
what years honestly I can't say exactly but
каких годах честно Точно не скажу но
definitely in the seventies because my uh
семидесятых точно се потому что у меня э
grandmother she lived in Kyrgyzstan Well she's like
бабушка она жила в Киргизии Ну она типа
from Ukraine but in Kyrgyzstan she was a
с Украины но в Киргизстан она была
doctor that is she was under the Union and my
врачом то есть её при Союзе и у меня
mother grew up in Kyrgyzstan she
мама выросла в Кыргызстане то она
said that it was I don't know what
говорила что было я не знаю какие это
years it was my mother fifty eight it
года у меня мама пятьдесят восьмого это
also turns out somewhere in the sixties
тоже получается где-то шестидесятые
seventies that there were a lot of Uyghurs
семидесятые что было уйгуров много
moved Well ran away from China then there was
переселилась Ну убежала из Китая тогда
persecution of them Yes in these
там гонения были на них Да вот в эти
regions Yeah yeah yeah Just in those
регионы Угу угу да Как раз таки вот в те
years a lot of settlements from China that
года многое поселение с Китая которые
were here Urumqi is essentially Urumqi Yes the
были вот Урумчи это по сути Урумчи Да
capital like yeah Uyghur And they Hungary
столица типа да Уйгур Вот и они Венгрию
Sweden and Kazakhstan
швецию и вот Казахстан вот эти вот
I know these countries now there in general  harshly in this
знаю да сейчас там вообще жёстко в этом
sinno Uyghur district there they carried out a
синно уйгурском округе там поводили
complete, as it were, restriction of
полный как бы ограничение
rights and inspection almost chipping
прав да досмотр чуть ли не чипирование
there conditionally Yes, children,
там условно Да детей
women in general, China is like ours Many people
женщин в общем Китай у нас как Многие
think that China Only China lives there,
думают что Китай Там живут только Китай
yes, but here is the sinno Uyghur Autonomous District
да но вот синн уйгурский автономный окру
It is a huge region, huge Tibet - These are
Он огромный регион огромный Тибет - Это
also not Chinese, also captured That is, China is
тоже не китайцы тоже захваченные То есть
essentially like an Empire in
Китай - это по сути как Империя в
which there are huge territories of other
которой есть огромные территории других
peoples Yes, others Yes, yes,
народов Да других Да да
but they appropriated everything to China this yes, it
да но все присвоили Китаю это да это ж
turns out that this, these territories
получается вот этот вот эти территории
Uyghur It was East Turkestan Yes, it was
Уйгур Это был Восточный Туркестан Да
called dach correctly Yes, so you
называлось дач правильно Да так что ты
said so in vain that you do not know such a nation
так зря сказал что ты такую нацию не
I know everything yes yes yes I apologize I
знаешь я всё знаю да да да Извиняюсь
apologize it's just 98 probably Protsev,
Извиняюсь просто 98 наверно Процев
your Uyghur language is
вот уйгурский у вас на узбекский язык
more similar to Uzbek yes it turns out yes similar yes it is
больше похож да получается да похож да
one group and Kazak is Kazakh Well,
это одна группа а каза казахский А ну ты
if you grew up in Kazakhstan, then you understand
если вырос в Казахстане то ты понимаешь
without knowing Kazakh Yes, I was just
без знаю казахский Да мне просто
wondering how much the Uyghurs
интересно было насколько уйгуры казахов
understand Kazakhs without an interpreter No,
понимают без переводчика Нет без проблем
absolutely no problem, you too  Turkic language they are all
абсолютно ти тоже тюркский язык они все
similar No well Turkic for example
похожие Не ну тюркский например вот у
we also have Slavic languages ​​there is
нас есть тоже славянские языки есть
Ukrainian and Slovak Ukrainian
украинский и словацкий украинский
for example and Belarusian And there is Ukrainian
например и белорусский А есть украинский
and for example Croatian Yes for example it
и например хорватский Да например он
can be a little or there Serbian it is already
может чуть-чуть или там сербский он уже
under the influence of the fact that they lived for a long time in
под влиянием того что они долго жили в
different regions it was formed under the
разных регионах формировалось под
influence of other cultures and changed
влиянием других культур и изменялись
too yes I am interested in what I know that
тоже да мне интересно по что я знаю что
Uyghur and Uzbek are very closely
уйгурский с узбекским очень близкое
related Yeah I was interested or
родство Угу Мне было интересно или
Kazakh Yes
казахский Да
also Well approximately Yes also many
также Ну приблизительно Да также многие
words are similar many words are taken from
слова похожие многие слова взяты из
Kazakh Gur type in fact one this is
казахского Гурского типа по сути одно
when the Mongols captured Rus'
это когда вот это монголы захватили Русь
that is to Moscow Moscow he also
то есть в Москву Московский он же
received a label From the Khan of this
получал ярлык У Хана у этого
Mongolian and these this label in
монгольского и эти этот ярлык на
Uyghur writing was written in Uyghur Yes
уйгурском письме писался на уйгурском Да
because the Mongols did not have such a thing about
потому что у монголо не было такого об
Yes what is it called in your I don’t speak in
Да как как называется у вас не говорю на
Ancient Irish And in Ancient I thought
Древнем ирском А на Древнем Я думал
some name of the tale Yes so that on
какое-то название сказа Да так что на
Dr yes and well these wars
дре да и ну эти войны
throughout the world in every country  their own
на весь мир в каждой стране своя
war Everyone must
война Каждый должен
endure I got it Okay All the best to you and you
терпеть понял Хорошо Всего хорошего тебе
too don't switch you
тоже не переключайтесь
remember we'll probably get into some Stream no I'm just curious
наверно нет мне просто интересно
talk to me tla Ukra but I'm not from
поговори меня тла Укра но я не из
Ukraine Finn
украи Финн
Look I'm from St. Petersburg myself But I've been living in
Смотри я сам из Питера родом Но живу в
Finland for 18 years in 2 years it will be
Финляндии уже 18 лет через 2 года будет
twenty I put a VIP on Ukraine
двадцатка я ставил випе на Украин
talked to Ukrainians How do you feel about the
общался с украинцами Как вы относитесь к
Finns Yes and then I said that I was from St. Petersburg
Финам Да а потом говорил что я из Питера
and watched how their attitude changed And where are
и смотрел как у них менялось отношение А
you from we are from Moldova
вы откуда мы с Молдовы
Comrade these gases Yes my father's last name is
Камрад эти газы Да у меня отец
GAUZ last name is
ГАУЗ фамилия фамилия
floors
полы
Ogly didn't stand
Оглы не стоял
in tamm in was a candidate in No our last name was
в тамм в кандидат был в Нет наша фамилия
standing and there
стоя а там
stood I got it damn Handsome Turks And you are well
стояло понял блин Красавцы тюрки А вы
Orthodox so yes we have
это ну православные так да у нас
Orthodox I got it how are you in
православные понял как там у вас в
Moldova May Sandu
Молдове мая Санду
won you don't like her Well for the sake of
победила не нравится вам она Ну ради
Europe it's possible But everything is
Европы можно Но дорого всё
expensive Listen I lived in Russia in St. Petersburg
дорого Слушай я жил в России в Питере да
and now I live in Finland I say Well it's
и сейчас живу в Финляндии Я говорю Ну ту
better for Russia It's better to be with Europe I'm
России лучше Лучше быть с Европой я сам
Russian myself yes on  half And what city do you
русский да на половину А в каком городе
live in Tampa
живёте тампе
Tampa I know Tampa yes and it turns out
тампе Я знаю тампе да и получается у
my mother is Russian Yes dad Gus he
меня мама русская Да папа Гус он он в
studied in St. Petersburg and stayed here well during the
Питере учился и остался тут ну При
Soviet Union it was and stayed I have
Советском Союзе это было и остался Я
never been to Gagauzia Yes but I know he is
никогда не был в Гагаузии Да но зна он
somewhere I don't remember what it was called
где-то я не помню как это
uh the village was called in short it is not in
ээ деревня называлась короче это он не в
Comrat itself so and I I ca
самом Комрате так
n't remember I'm trying to
а я я не вспомню Я вот сейчас пробую
remember now it was called something it is
вспомнить она как-то называлась это
small it is not a city yes that is he is
небольшая это не не город да то есть он
in a village like He was born during the Soviet Union
в деревне типа Родился он при Союзе во
but he he said that there are
но он он рассказывал что там гагаузов
very few Gagauz there very few and everyone is leaving
очень мало очень мало и все разъезжаются
Therefore in Germany our parents are in
Поэтому в Германии у нас родители в
Germany For example, to earn money We are
Германии Вот например на заработках Мы
together only why not to
вдвоём только вот а что же не в
Moscow because in Germany they
Москву потому что в Германии лучше
pay better Moscow also a lot of people go
Платят то Моск тоже много кто едет то А
then Why are you afraid of Maya
что же вы тогда Боитесь маю
Sandu We are not afraid of her we just have prices
Санду Мы её не боимся у нас просто цены
and people people are very Yes people rebel
и у людей люди очень Да бунтуют люди
want to go there and there she is more for Europe
хотят и туда и туда она больше за Европу
Well since both there and there you understand better
Ну так как и туда и туда понимаешь лучше
But parents are not in Russia  let's go to
Вот родители же не в Россию поехали а в
Germany because it's better there yes in
Германию потому что там лучше да в
Europe it's better to strive for the
Европе вс-таки лучше лучше тянуться к
European level with you And how did you
европейскому уровню у вас А как в
even
Финляндию вообще
move to Finland I studied at first then I
перебрались Я учился сначала так потом я
entered the master's program and I was
на магистратуру поступил и Меня
invited to the University of Tampere
пригласили в университет города тампера
I wrote a dissertation on applied mathematics
я по прикладной математике диссертацию
and stayed there Yes and I teach now
писал и там остался Да и преподаю Сейчас
at the
в
university That is, I learned Yes so what
университете То есть я выучи Да так что
And what is the average salary Well, of a
А какая средняя зарплата Ну
teacher at a university Well, for me, I don't
преподавателя в ВУЗе Ну у меня у меня я
know how Average I can't but I didn't
не знаю как Средняя не могу да я же не
ask everyone Yes, for me in euros it
опрашивал всех Да у меня в евро
turns out to be 4,000
получается 4.000
euros small
евро небольшая
Oh is this gross or not that's before
Ой это бруто или нето это до вычета
taxes tax deductions we get here for
налогов вычеты налогов у нас получается
me With
вот у меня При
such salaries, so 11%
таком при таких зарплатах так 11%
comes out to tax
получается налог
that is 4,440 euros somewhere goes yes that is
то есть 4 440 евро где-то уходит да то
this And here are the others there well for housing for
есть это А вот другие там ну за жильё за
what That's what everything is like with you Look,
что Вот какие у вас всё Смотри э дешевле
food is cheaper cheaper than in Russia yes
продукты дешевле чем в России да
cars are cheaper than in Russia in Russia
автомобили дешевле чем в России в России
some wild fashions I don't know how it
какие-то дикие поши я не знаю как у нас
was like that with us Yes in Russia it's stupidly more expensive
так было Да в России тупо дороже тачку
take a car Here are the phones too That is, the
взять Вот телефоны также То есть тут и
standard of living is higher here And the salaries are higher and the
уровень жизни выше Да и зарплаты выше а
prices are about the same or
цены приблизительно одинаковые либо в
even higher in Russia that's all these fables
России выше даже вот и всё вот эти басни
about utilities And so on it's all nonsense Yeah
про коммуналку И так дальше это всё бред
Phew Yeah And you get it like
Угу Уф Угу А у вас получается ну типа у
you have a Romanian passport no we don't have
вас румынский паспорт есть не у нас нет
we only Moldovans only Moldova Yes
у нас только молдовки только Молдова Да
because I know from Transnistria
потому что я знаю вот из Приднестровья
they make Romanian and also
они делают и румынский Ещё себе и
Russian for themselves they have a bunch of passports in general
русский ониче вообще там куча паспортов
they are
они
Ukrainian No not we what else
украинский Нет не у нас что к ещё сестра
our sister in my opinion Yes there are three of you too Yes yes yes
наша по-моему Да тоже вас трое
sister hundred
Да да да сестра ста
towers and by the way it turns out you are studying
башн а вы кстати получается вот учитесь
now in school or already somewhere at the
сейчас в школе или уже где-то в
university Komrat University in
университете университет камрат в
Comrat yes And what are you studying to be
Комрате да А на кого учитесь
linguists what exactly English German
лингвисты что именно английский немецкий
understood that is after all you are not going to Russia
понял то есть всё-таки не в России
yes
собираетесь да
for joining the European Union how did you
за вступление в Евросоюз вы как
vote we will join Yes we are for that is you
голосовали вступим Да мы за а то есть вы
were against Ma Santu but for joining the
были против ма Санту но за вступление в
European Union No no we are not against we are against
Евросоюз Да нет мы не против мы против
high prices that's what Well you voted
цен больших вот что Ну вот голосовал ты
in the referendum  For what For my for
на референдуме За что За мою за
joining for joining the European Union Yes, I
вступление за вступление в Евросоюз Да
understand because well It would be strange if
понял потому что ну Было бы странно если
you were against the
вы были против
European Union not with us many go and
Евросоюза не у нас многие ездят
earn money at our place here at our
зарабатывают у на вот
mother ours went
мама у нас поехала
And who is our
наша А кто нам
Tanya I forgot who Tanya is
Танька я забыл кто
our grandmother's wife Tanya went too that's
Танька жена нашего ба поехала ещё Таня
why many went and you have
вот поэтому многие поехали а у вас
relatives in
родственники в
Ukraine lno how do they feel now they didn't
Украине льно как они относятся сейчас не
come to you because of the war no They
приехали к вам из-за войны не Они там
stayed there She works at the
остались Она работает на
market
привозе
she she just wants to live just to
она она хочет просто жить просто
earn money And what is she telling you about this war
зарабатывать А что она про эту войну вам
like well there if she lives there
говорить типа ну там если она там живёт
She knows better doesn't like doesn't like doesn't
Она лучше знает не любит не любит не
like it all but she still communicates with us
нравится ей это всё но с нами всё равно
communicates how does she you asked
общается как она вам вот вы е спрашивали
there who is to blame Putin Zelensky what does she say
там кто виноват Путин Зеленский что она
what are you asking Well how do you this is
говорит что просите Ну как вы вот это
your relative She says this is Putin
ваша родственница Она говорит это Путин
Zelensky who is to blame for the war oh everyone
Зеленский кто виноват в войне ой всех
she blames everyone and this and that first there
она винит всех и того и того сначала
was Putin now for And what do you
была запутина теперь за А вы как
think Who is to blame what Sorry,
считаете Кто виноват что Простите а вы
what do you think Who is to
как считаете Кто
blame We think that the one who started is to blame
виноват Мы считаем что виноват тот кто
understood  Do you think so too yes also yes Well
понял А вы тоже так считаю да тоже да Ну
we are also afraid to say something because
Мы тоже боимся как-то сказать потому что
we have such a thing here well by the way many of us
у нас тут такое ну у нас многие кстати
came when it started many of us
приезжали когда началось у нас многие
came
приезжали
there from Vinnitsa from
там из Винницы из
Lviv so there were a lot of people
Львова поэтому много людей было
understood And sister What does the
понял А сестра Кем работает та что
eldest one do She studies Studying to be a
старшая Учится Учится на
linguist The two of us are not there the
кого на лингвиста Мы вдвоём не там
third one and the third one is our Katya she
третья ещ а третье - это наша Катя она
studies management And why do you have
учится на менеджменте А что у вас имена
such Russian names and not ours But we
такие русские а не у нас Но у нас всех
call all those who are more Orthodox by
кто именно больше православные называют
Russian names because for example to
русскими именами потому что например
have breakfast bu angel's day well that's why
завтракать бу день ангела ну поэтому у
everything is like that with us yes That is of course possible Well we
нас всё так да То есть можно конечно Ну
also have Bashkan Gazi Evgeniya tsu Well
тоже вот у нас башкан гази Евгения цу Ну
yes I also look That is that
да я тоже смотре Вот вот то есть у нас
all our names are Russian and there are few Gagauz
все имена русские и гагаузов мало
left and that's why when they call them there and
осталось и поэтому когда там называют и
many of us are conditional For example
многие же у нас условно Вот например
our mother she is Jewish and Russian That is because of
мама наша она еврейка и русская То есть
this we have such a mixture that And
у нас из-за этого смешение такое что А у
your dad is GAUZ also yes like me Damn
вас папа ГАУЗ тоже да как у меня Блин
only my mother is just Russian and
только у меня мама просто русская а у
you also have a Jewish and Russian mother yes yes that's
вас ещё мама еврейка и русская то да вот
why we have such well we have a
да поэтому у нас такой ну у нас мишени
complete target we have some generally
полная у нас некоторые есть вообще
only Russian guys there are some
только русские ребята есть кто-то вот
Romanians who study for example Well here are the guys
румыны Кто учится например Ну вот ребята
who are moving Who where and there are no
там кто переезжает Кто куда а нету
some Well I heard that in this
каких-то Вот я слышал что в этом в
Kremlin they declared that Gagauzia should
Кремле заявляли что Гагаузия должна
get there to separate from Moldova
получить там отделиться от Молдовы
something like that No these are separatist
что-то такое Нет это сепаратистские
sentiments as if they have always been in
настроения как бы они всегда были в
Gagauzia Who is different but the majority of course are
гагаузи Кто как но большинство конечно
for joining Russia in general and how to
за присоединение вообще к России а как
rush to Russia if
преться к России если тут
Ukraine is here Well we have such people
Украина Ну у нас такие люди
therefore well I'll run on Okay
по поэтому хорошо побегу дальше О'кей
Let's have a good
Давайте Хорошего вам
evening So now I am
вечера Так теперь я
this as I am the last name of the priest on
этот как я фамилия попа на
Glu they have the same last names there Yes on oglu and Well
Глу у них же там фамилии Да на оглу а Ну
put a plus Who do we have from
поставьте плюсик Кто у нас есть из
Moldova and put three threes if there is
Молдовы а поставьте три троечки если
someone from Gagauzia or
есть кто-то из гагаузи или
GAUZ Salam aleikum salam aleikum aleikum
ГАУЗ Салам алейкум салам алейкум алейкум
assam you are from Tajikistan from
ассам ты из Таджикистана из
Tajikistan from Dagestan  Dagestan
Таджикистана с Дагестана Дагестана
Avari Dargin Dargin Handsome my
авари даргинец даргинец Красава у меня
father is Avar
отец аварец
Mom is from Lav Where are you from now I live
Мама из из Лав Ты откуда сам сейчас живу
in Ukraine I live in
в Украине живу в
Ukraine Why Because in the nineties
Украине Почему Потому что в девяностых
when there was persecution of us Muslims in
когда были гонения на нас мусульман в
Russia yes mom and dad moved to
России да мама и папа переехали в
Ukraine to the city of Kharkov city of Kharkov
Украину в город Харьков город Харьков
There Russians do not like us Russians
Там Русские не любят нас русские
hate us Dagestan eh only they like
ненавидят нас Дагестан э толь они как
Look when some athlete
Смотри когда какой-то спортсмен
wins they say it is a Russian
выигрывает они говорят это русский
athlete yes if from Dagestan when
спортсмен да если из Дагестана когда
something bad someone does o says Oh
что-то плохое кто-то сделат о говорит О
this is some they call us I call There is such There is such
это какой-то они нами называю называю
you are a Muslim
Есть такое Есть такое ты мусульманин
brother Muslim yes Muslims Yes and you and
брат Мусульманин да мусульмани Да а ты а
you do you serve Cairo or not serve or not
ты ты каиру служишь или нет служишь или
serve cafe Well Putin
нет служишь кафе Ну Путин
cafe what so he cafe And our brothers and
кафн что так он кафер А наших братьев и
sisters are
сестёр
locked up in prisons of ours how many of our
закрывают в тюрьмы наших сколько наших
Muslim brothers are sitting in Russian yu
братьев мусульман сидит по российских ю
in Syria mule Assad and now he was taken to
в Сирии мул Асад и сейчас его взяли в
Moscow
Москву
hid did you see How many Muslims yuh
спрятали ты видел Сколько мусульман юх
killed brother Behind you What kind of flag is
убита брат У тебя сзади Это что за флаг
this flag  United States of America they
это флаг Соединённых Штатов Америки они
support us
поддерживают нас
Muslims now Are you serious
мусульман сейчас Серьёзно что ли
seriously look at the
говоришь серьёзно посмотри
vice president of the United States of
вице-президент Соединённых Штатов
America who is Ilya
Америки кто Иля
Ibrahim from Pakistan
ибрахим родом родом из Пакистана
and what is America doing to Muslims America
а что Америка делает мусульманам Америка
helps Muslims America wants the
помогает мусульманам Америка хочет
liberation of Muslims from Russia Russia
освобождение мусульман от России Росси
Yes what did it do in Syria helped
Да она что сделала в Сирии помогла
America helped in Syria to overthrow Assad
Америка помогла в Сирии свергнуть асада
who mocked Muslims even Assad's
который издевался над мусульманами ещё
dad haye Alawites these mocked
папа асада хае алавиты эти издевались
Muslims if not
мусульманами если нери
Americans to break Assad's howl and then
амери разбить вой асада и потом
the Mujahideen entered Damascus entered Homs entered
моджахеды вошли в Дамаск зашли в Хомс
Homs entered Hama You saw It
зашли в Хомс зашли в хаму Ты видел Это у
warmed your heart warmed your heart
тебя грело сердце грело серце
And what is
А что
America doing to the
Америка делает
Palestinians America helps the Palestinians
палестинца Америка помогает палестинцы
America helps food in Gaza
Америка помогает продовольствие в газу
you saw it dropped food from planes in Gaza
скидывает ты видел с самолётов скидывала
so that children could have gas and what about
продукты в газу чтобы дети газ а что
Dagestan Russia does nothing for
Дагестан Россия ничего не делает для
gas you saw so that children could bring gas to
газа ты видел чтобы дети газы привезли в
Dagestan there is no vacation but in America there is
Дагестан отдыхать нету а в Америке есть
in America there is the state of California the state of
в Америке есть штат Калифорния штат
California  look in the state of California Yes, they
Калифорния смотри в штат Калифорния Да
brought
привезли
1,488 children from the Gaza Strip to rest
1488 детей из Сектора Газа отдыхать
Placed them in children's camps for
Разместили в детских лагерях
free America paid for the
бесплатно Америка проплати для того
children of Gaza to be safe while
чтобы дети газы были в безопасности пока
the war is going on and Russia Why does Russia
Война идёт а Россия Почему Россия
help Africa help Korea there but
помогает Африке помогает там Корея
won't help Muslims Why
какой-то а мусульманам не поможет Почему
won't they bring Dagestan Makhachkala Yes, they won't
не привезут Дагестан Махачкалу Да не
bring Jews they brought Yes, they brought a lot to the Makhachkala airport I do
привезут евреев привозили Да в аэропорт
n't know how many they brought Our village even Our
привезли не знаю Наше село даже Наше
village 100 something people and so every
село 100 чем-то человек и так каждое
village in every city where there are 100 with something people there is no
село каж города где 100 с чем человек
such thing in Chechnya only 50
нет такого в Чечню только 50 прили
Muslims came look Russians don't respect
мусульман смотри русские не уважают
Muslims they say that these are
мусульман они говорят что это
some kind of I read their telegrams they say they
какие-то я читал их телеграмы они
overthrew Ana What are they talking about
говорят си свергли Ана Они что они про
our Koran
Коран наш
they say Yes, they come to
говорят они говорят Да они приезжают в
Dagestan like they are Russian kings but in
Дагестан типа они русские короли а в
Moscow no you can't make a mosque Why do
Москве нет мечеть нельзя делать Почему
our brothers pray in apartments in Moscow
наши братья молятся на квартирах в Моск
How many swords are in Moscow in Mom
в Сколько в Москве мече в моме потому
because Iblis
что иблис
Iblis controls
иблис управляет
these
этими
controls Putin doesn't  Muslim nelma and
управля Путин же не мусульманин нельма и
what do they say They say Russia is an
что они говорят Они говорят Россия - это
Orthodox country all there should be no Islam
православная страна всё никакого Ислама
here
тут не должно быть
when there was a vote so that the
когда голосование было чтобы на купюрах
Kazan mosque would be put on the banknotes on the
сделали казанскую мечеть на купюрах
ruble banknotes Russians these
рублёвых русские эти
what said no Muslim symbols there should
что сказал никаких мусульманских тут не
be symbols of
должно быть символов символов
BT and Joe Biden What did he do to Palestine
БТ а Джо байден Что делал палестине
helped Palestine Joe Biden Palestine
помогал палестине джо байден палестине
Joe Biden subhanallah
джо байден субханалла
Brother you are you in Dagestan where do you live
Брат ты ты в Дагестане где живёшь
Dagestan where do you live in Khasavyurt
Дагестане где живёшь в Хасавюрте
Khasavyurt Khasavyurt is a very ancient city
хасавьюрт хасавьюрт очень древний город
you know the villages and Shamil's mother you know
ты знаешь селени и мама Шамиля знаешь
Shami you know
Шами знае
Hafiz Brother you are
Хафиз Брат ты
Hafiz My respects to you so
Хафиз Моё почтение тение те так вот
tell me why
скажи почему
our contemporaries have scored
наши современники забили
mother as a zab no one has forgotten him we
мамаша как заб никто его не забыл у нас
have at most a portrait of Shamil's portrait and things are going badly
есть а дела шат
or Brother look
или Брат смотри
you see this whole situation from that side
ты с той стороны видишь так эту всю
even And which we see from there from here This is a
даже А который мы видим отту отсюда Это
completely different
вообще другая
picture Joe Biden did against Israel
картина Джо байден делал против Израиля
Joe Biden look Joe  Biden Did not
Джо байден смотри Джо байден Не
seize our Dagestan Our Dagestan
захватывал наш Дагестан наш Дагестан
was seized by
захватила
Russia When did they seize Dagestan If there was
Россия когда захватили Дагестан если
no Russia If there was no Russia
России не было бы если России не было бы
What would have happened to Dagestan What would have been an
что было бы с дагестаном что был бы
independent Dagestan or would we be friends with Turkey
Независимый Дагестан или мы бы с Турцией
with Muslim countries Why
дружили с мусульманскими странами Почему
look Azerbaijan exists Yes Kazakhstan
смотри Азербайджан есть да Казахстан
exists But Dagestan cannot be free
есть а Дагестан не может быть свободным
Why freedom Why are we great
Почему свобод Почему мы великие
Muslim confederation should be and
мусульманская конфедерация должна быть а
not some Russia Why are we strangers to them
не какая-то Россия Почему мы для них
strangers They want to take resources from us
чужие чужие они хотят у нас брать
take money and take in You
ресурсы брать деньги и брать во иты
now live in Ukraine lived in Ukraine
сейчас в Украине живёшь жил в Украине
now I live in Europe In what city did I live
сейчас живу в Европе в каком городе жил
in Kharkov in ha When my parents
в харкове в ха У меня родители когда
fled from the war in Dagestan they were in
убежали от войны в Дагестане были в
Kharkov I was in Chernigov when
Харьков Я был в Чернигове когда
when about 34 years ago And what
когда года 34 года назад а что
did Gulya do there
делал Гуля там
relatives understood And how are they now the
родственники понял А как они сейчас
war is not in Ukraine Ukraine They are they
война не в Украине Украине Они они
now in Germany I think understood And they are
сейчас в Германии кажется понял а они
citizens of what country what
граждане какой страны какой
country now Well now they live in Germany I do
страны сейчас ну сейчас в Германии живут
n’t know Well and citizens of Russia Ukraine
не знаю ну а граждане России Украины
Russia Ukraine Ukraine understood And how do they
России Украины Украины понял и как они
say that Russia attacked  Ukraine
говорят что что Россия напала на Украину
Ukraine they don't talk about this They don't talk about this every
Украину про этото не говорят Они каждый
time when someone calls them
раз когда к ним звонит
What is it they didn't
Что такое
say anything bad about Putin I don't know Putin Look expelled
говорили не знаю вот Путин Смотри изгнал
How many Muslims expelled How many are in
Сколько мусульман изгнал Сколько в
prisons and Putin He is a non-
тюрмах и Путин Он же гр
believer who is Putin for
неверующий кто Путин для
you America has nothing to do with Dagestan America
тебя Америка не имеет Дагестану ничего
lives there Americans have been talking about
Америка жит там амери зах говорили про
America now Russia has captured Dagestan
Америку сейчас Россия захватила Дагестан
and Shamil's mother destroyed the Muslims or what
и мама Шамиля уничтожила то мусульман
Ukraine is the president so what does
что ли Украины президент так причём
Ukraine not capture Dagestan you are from
Украина не захватила Дагестан ты из
Dagestan my roots are from Dagestan our
Дагестана мои корни из Дагестана наш
people are conquered all Dargins Kumyks Laks
народ покорён все даргинцы кумыки лакцы
Tabasarans all-all are conquered Avars are
табасаранцы все-все покорены аварцы
conquered
покорены
Avars Dagestan has always been free
аварцы Дагестан всегда был свободный
when the Mongols came with Timur yes our
когда монголы пришли с Тимуром да наши
ancestors stood up together with the wars and recaptured the
предки вместе с войнами встали и отбили
territories And now what And now what do you
территории А сейчас что А сейчас что ты
agree that you agree that we are
согласен что ты согласен что мы для
nobody for the Russians
русских никто для руских
nobody for the Russians you were in Moscow you were in
никто никто ты был в Москве ты был в
Moscow yes And how they looked at you they
Москве да И как на тебя смотрели на тебя
looked at you I
смотрели я
was
был
m exactly the Russians
м именно русские
they think we have God
они считают у нас Боже
How can I
Как
say  wild or something like that I don't
сказать диким или что-то такое не
know they say they
знаю они говорят
came from their villages like that they
приехали своих аулов вот так они
say you know why those who come from here
говорят знаешь почему которые отсюда
who stand up and live stand up
едут которые встане живут встане такие
they don't do such things because I don't
вещи они не делают потому что их не
leave them here the same people as they are
оставляю здесь такие же люди как они
in short And when
короче А когда
they are back and forth in Russia
они в Росси
they
туда-сюда они
already do what they want In short they already
уже делают что хотят Короче они уже
get freedom and because of
получают свободу и изза
several 105 how much is this considered all of
несколько 105 сколько это считают весь
Dagestan like that no Look when a Russian
дагистан такими нет Смотри когда русский
kills or beats something there they
там что-то убивает или бьёт они из-за
don't consider all Russians bad because of this they
этого не считают всех русских плохими
hate us Dagestanis they
они нас ненавидят дагестанцев они
use This is only for a reason Yes they
используют Это только для повода Да они
all consider us Yes they consider us they
все нас считают Да они считают нас
look they say that we lived
они вот смотри они говорят что мы жили
barefoot and naked they don't know that Derbent is the
босые и голые они не знают что Дербент
oldest city the oldest city in Russia
древнейший город древнейший город России
turf you know this you know 5,000 years
дерн ты это знаешь знаешь 5.000 лет
5,000
5.000
years Moscow doesn't exist Even 2000 2000 years and
лет Москвы нету Даже 2000 2000 лет а
5000 der 5000 der it stood on the Great Silk
5000 дер 5000 дер он на Великом шёлком
Road the road stood our ancestors
пути стоял шком пути стоял наши предки
were in civilization  when Russians still
были в цивилизации когда русские ещё
ran like on trees or whoever ran
бегали как на деревьях или кто там бегал
in the woods And now they Using everything
в лесах А сейчас они Пользуясь всем
Western they tell us Dagestanis that you we
западным нам говорят дагестанцам что вы
gave you everything we they are like
мы вам всё дали мы они как Господа
some kind of Lord they came conquered killed
какие-то они пришли завоевали убили
how many of our ancestors are they taking
сколько наших предков забирают сейчас
all the money from Dagestan now my
все деньги из Дагестана у меня
relatives live in Makhachkala they say there is a power
родственники живут в Махачкале говорят
outage here you have I
отключение света есть вот у вас есть
turn off the light in
отключаю све
the summer Yes why don't
кнот летом Да почему в Москве не
they turn off in Moscow they take our electricity from
отключают они электрику у нас из
Dagestan and drag it to Moscow
Дагестана забирают и в Москву
you know so that Muscovites
перетягивают понимаешь чтобы москвичи
have discos Yes with Christmas trees And our
были с дискотеками Да с ёлочками А наши
children have to sit without light sit without
дети должны сидеть без света сидеть без
light So that's how much is the salary
света Так так вот сколько зарплата
now in Dagestan ub Dane u te about
сейчас в Дагестане уб Дане у те про
Russia I would not like to talk now I well about the one
Россию я не хотел бы сейчас говорю я ну
you were talking about Palestine about
про который ты говорил про палестину про
America Why look Why don't you
Америку Почему смотри Почему ты не
want to talk about Russia Palestine is
хочешь говорить про Россию Палестина
far away America is far away and you are in Dagestan and
далеко Америка далеко а ты в Дагестане и
Russia in Dagestan it is Russia not
Россия в Дагестане она Россия не
Palestine and not America takes your
Палестина и не Америка забирает у тебя
money takes your brothers and sisters
деньги забирает твоих братьев и сестёр
Russia  takes and you sit instead of
Россия забирает а ты сидишь вместо того
talking why Moscow wait don't
поговорить почему Москва подожди не
interrupt when an elder speaks if you are a
перебивай когда старший говорит если ты
Muslim You should not interrupt a
мусульманин Ты не должен перебивать
hundred
ста
years so what So if you are a Muslim
года так что Так что если ты мусульманин
if you are a Muslim You should respect your
если ты мусульманин Ты должен уважать
elders you should respect a hundred respect
старши ты должен уважать ста уважаешь
respect
уважаешь
dabra say I respect you say I you
дабра скажи Я вас уважаю скажи я
what say I respect you say I
вас что скажи Я вас уважаю скажи Я вас
respect you Well what's the difference I'm just
уважаю Ну какая разница Я же просто
saying Why can't you say
говоришь Да почему ты не можешь сказать
I respect you an elder person oh an elder
Я вас уважаю старший человек ужа старший
person and why should I
человек а почему я это должен
say this stop you are definitely a Muslim
говорить стоп ты точно мусульманин
Muslim alhamdulillah brother T Do you
мусульманин альхамдулиллях брат Т Ты
follow Muslim traditions or have
следуешь мусульманским традиция или
you just read and read and
просто ты начитался и всё начитался и
everything Do you respect your elders respect your elders
всё Ты уважаешь старших уважаешь старших
yes tell me I respect you as an elder person
да скажи мне я вас как старшего человека
respect And why should I
уважаю А почему я так должен
say this Why are you embarrassed are you
говорить Почему ты стесняешься ты
embarrassed of your following respect your
стесняешься своего следования уважать
elders brother as an elder tell me I
старших брат как старшего скажи я вас
respect you as an elder person respect a person
как старшего человека уважаю человека
look brother as an elder I respect  I
уважаю смотри брат как старшего уважаю я
you Well how is everything enough for me
тебя Ну как всё мне достаточно
enough you said that like Stasha I respect
достаточно ты сказал что как сташа
Everything I believe that a Muslim Okay let's
уважаю Всё я верю что мусульманин Окей
talk Next look how much is your
говорим Дальше смотри сколько у вас в
salary in Dagestan what is
Дагестане зарплата
this salary money How much do they pay
как это зарплата деньги Сколько платят
for work sko pay for work Well it depends on
за работу ско платят за работу Ну смотря
what kind of work brother What kind of work do
какая работа брат У тебя какая работа у
you have what kind of work do you have
тебя какая
I don't work at the moment Brother and
я на данный момент я не работаю Брат а
why and why am I
почему а почему
studying for whom for whom there is
учусь на кого на
no one I just study Arabic you
кого не на кого просто учу Арабский это
will accept this I know and at some school
примете Я знаю а в школе какой-то учится
or at a university or at a university And how old are you And how old are you
или в университе у или в университете А
And how old are you How
сколько тебе лет А сколько тебе лет А
old are you I am 19
сколько тебе лет Сколько тебе лет Мне 19
19 and work Why don't you
19 а работать Почему не идёшь Почему не
go Why don't you go I say that brother I am studying
идёшь говорю что брат
Inshallah that's when I will learn when I will
учусь иншалла вот когда я научусь когда
finish all this
вот это всё закончу
then I will go I work Are you definitely studying the Koran
потом пойду я работаю Ты точно Коран
Yes brother How old was the wife of
изучаешь Да брат Сколько лет было жене
Mohammed what How old was the wife of
магамета что Сколько лет было жене
Mohammed the prophet Muhammad Brother
Магомета пророка Мухаммеда Брат
look you say you study the Koran even I
смотри ты говоришь изучаешь Коран даже Я
asked how old was the wife of
спросил сколько лет было жене
Mohammed [ __ ] those
Мухаммеда сри те
questions ask  The
вопро говори
Koran brother
Коран брат
happens with the translation which teaches the whole
бывает с переводом который учат всей
history everything
истории все
there purely without nature without anything which the
туда чисто без природа без ничего
Koran
который Коран
is read
читают
understood what kind of image it asked
понял какой это образ задавал
How old was the wife of the prophet Muhammad
Сколько лет было жене пророка Мухаммеда
Muhammad she was than the prophet ma 10 years old
Мухамеда она была чем пророк ма 10 лет
How old was she How old was she
Сколько ей лет было Сколько ей лет было
when you say when she was born When she
когда ты говоришь когда родилась Когда
died or what when she became when she
умерла или что когда она стала когда она
when she was born I know how old she
когда она родилась я знаю сколько лет ей
was when she became the wife of Muhammad
было когда она стала женой Мухаммеда
How old was she How old was she when she
Сколько ей лет было Сколько ей лет было
became I do
когда стала
n't know brother I don't
Не знаю брат не
remember 10 years old or 10 years old or
помню 10 лет было или 10 лет было или
8 what 10 years old she was or was
8 что 10 лет ей было или было
or when What are you talking about not Yes How old
или когда Ты о чём не Да Сколько лет
was this little girl when she
было маленькой этой девочке когда она
became the wife of the prophet Muhammad the prophet
стала женой пророка Мухаммеда пророка
Muhammad tell me brother I don't remember I don't know Well,
Мухаммеда говори же брат не помню не
take it now and
знаю А ну возьми сейчас узнай А ну
find out Well, take it now and find out
возьми сейчас
no You know
узнай не Ты же знаешь
brother 8 years old was 8 years old was eight
брат 8 лет было 8 лет было восемь
eight Well, you also now definitely
восемь Ну ты тоже сейчас по-любому
wrote somewhere Here I found out even no no
где-то написал Вот это узнал даже нет
How many wives did the prophet Muhammad
нет Сколько жён было у пророка Мухаммеда
Muhammad have Brother look you  now you ask
Мухаммеда Брат смотри ты сейчас задаёшь
questions I ask is it normal to
вопросы Я спрашиваю это нормально
have so many wives wives you How many wives do you think are
столько жён иметь жёны ты Сколько жён
normal how many wives do you think are
считаешь нормально сколько жн считаешь
normal
нормально
and according to the Koran four are allowed
а нормально по Корану разрешено четыре
But I'm probably not going to
Но я не собираюсь наверное четыре жем
take four wives And what are you not
брать А что Не собираешь Аче не
going to? Are you not going to? There is no such
собираешься нету такой
opportunity Why
возможности Почему
Why do I think I couldn't I couldn't
Почему я думаю не смог
what to satisfy them to satisfy no so that
бы не смог бы что удовлетворить их
everything would be
удовлетворить нет чтобы равно всё было
shorter than each
короче каждой
Zhenya Do you want at least one wife? You want one wife Well yes
Женя А хоть одну жену хочешь одну жену
At what age do you want to
да Во сколько лет хочешь
take those
брать те
in 3 years
через 3 года
probably understood And
наверно понял А
now with whom Yes you are an adult man
сейчас с кем да ты же взрослый мужчина
VS
взс
man How with whom do you sleep Well if
мужчина как с кем спишь Ну если у тебя
you don't have a wife with whom are you doing now You are talking about the World Cup if you don't have a wife you are 19 years old no
если у тебя нет жены тебе 19 лет нет
girlfriend with whom are you doing
девушки с кем ты
And what should I do with this Well
занимаешься А я что должен этим
at 19 your body already
заниматься Ну в 19 лет твой организм уже
requires it then somehow how do you
это требует то как-то ты как ты
satisfy your body the body
удовлетворяет свой организм организм
requires
требует
that religion does not
что религия не
allow I understand religion does not allow
разрешает я понимаю религия не разрешает
and there is some kind of hand there is some kind of hand and
а там рука есть какой-то есть какой-то а
what kind of those have you gone with now Well how well
что за у тебя теми сейчас пошли Ну как
19 years old I don't believe that a guy is 19 years old  there is
ну 19 лет я не верю что парень 19 лет
no
никак не имеет
life for brother
жизни на брат
China do you have two
Чина есть у тебя две
two Seriously Seriously
две Серьёзно Серьёзно
Seriously And
Серьёзно И
you do everything exactly the same for each wife
ты вот ровно каждой жене всё одинаково
Yes brother it's unreal the
делаешь Да брат это нереально
same somewhere more somewhere less
одинаково где-то больше где-то меньше
somewhere vice versa And you at all Without a wife Without a
где-то наоборот А ты вообще Без жены Без
wife I'm 43 years old I can afford Yes I'm like a
жены я 43 года я могу позволить Да я как
Sheikh no Sheikh that's four I want four
Шейх нет Шейх это четыре Я хочу четыре
wives now while two two I financially
жены сейчас пока две две я материально
provide for two Yes and you can't even have
обеспечиваю две Да а ты пока не можешь
one yet and the question question I
одну даже и вопрос вопрос У меня
have a life with two wives And with whom with
есть жизнь с двумя жёнами А у тебя с кем
whom you at what age Brother
кем ты во сколько Брат
got married
женился
18 seriously Yes with the first wife
18 серьёзно Да с первой женой
18 you have children brother
18 Дети есть у тебя брат есть
How many from the first wife four and from the
Сколько от первой жены четыре и от
second five
второй пять
question When are you planning to
вопрос Ты когда планируешь
do it when I get married that is
заняться когда поженюсь
another 3 years will you play with your
то есть ещё 3 года ты будешь баловаться
pen did you do it before or what And after
ручкой ты до во занимался что ли А после
18 Everything Became an adult the body
18 Всё Стал совершеннолетний организм
requires it
требует
you say got married at 18 and after
ты же говоришь в 18 женился да и после
18 began to do it And you want
18 стал заниматься А ты хочешь
22 And before I didn't do it before I still
22 А до во не занимался до вона ещё во
held back
сдерживался
Yes you can hold back until I will and I  up to
Да ты могу до во во сдержит а я до
2T I can't or what you won't be able to after that
2Т не смогу что ли не сможешь после во
already the body is not the same
уже организм вообще не тот уже
testosterone
тестостерон
just stands like that You have
просто стоит такой У тебя же есть
testosterone really really Yes bra gets up
тестостерон правда правда Да бра встаёт
and what do you do when it
и что ты делаешь когда он
stands Wait 3 years up to 2 up
стоит Подожди 3 года до 2
oh baby no need now testosterone
до оу малыш не надо сейчас тестостерон
testosterone I'll pour you with cold water lower lower
тестостерон я тебя водичкой холодной
Yes how do you
полью опусти опустись Да как ты его
calm him down how do you calm him down
успокаиваешь как ты его успокаиваешь
What is this topic now I don't know
Что за это сейчас темы пошли не знаю
Normal male topics And what male
Нормальные мужские темы А что мужские
topics And what always men mahi always
темы А что всегда мужчины махи всегда
talked about power about God about money and about
говорили о власти о Боге о деньгах и о
women these are always four eternal topics about
женщинах это всегда четыре вечных темы о
which a man If you watched yes in the
которых мужчина Если ты смотрел да в
Koran when the prophet Muhammad ibn us
Коране когда пророк Мухамед ибн нас
spoke he said there are four
говорил он говорил есть четыре
pious topics for a man this is God
благочестивых темы для мужчины это бог
Allah this is power this is money And this is a
Аллах это власть это деньги И это
woman
женщина
wife You are a Muslim how do you your
жена Ты же мусульманин как ты своего
testosterone Nago snake soothing I
тестостерон Наго змея успокаивающий
calm down Well these are stupid topics this is ses these are
успокаиваю Ну это тупые темы это сес это
not stupid topics if you are Muslim You
не тупые темы если ты мусульман Ты не
should not be afraid to communicate on these those a
должен бояться общаться на этих те
man or a woman this is a woman you can't
мужчина или женщина это женщина нельзя
talk to
говорить она
her you can't talk And a man should
ей нельзя говорить А мужчина должен
talk this is a sign  Judgment
говорить это признак Судного
Day what is the sign of the
дня что признак
court
суд
to talk about Well, about such
разговаривать ну примерно Вот таких
topics No, I'm not telling you The Prophet
темах Да нет не я тебе говорю Пророк
Muhammad ibn Nasim spoke about these topics
Мухаммед иб Насим говорил об этих темах
and said that these are pious topics
и говорил что это благочестивые темы
pious this is say who with to
благочестива это говори кто с к
Wednesday What is there he about his wife to communicate
сре Да что там он про его жену общаться
yes Why did he like the namer with each other and
да Почему он как намер друг с другом а
normally our ancestors always communicated about this
нормально наши предки всегда общались об
or how did they
этом или как они об этом
find out about this who will teach who will teach the youth to
узнавали кто научит кто научит юнца
handle his testosterone snake
обращаться со своим тестостерон змеем
if not the
если не
elders
старшие
look for example This I have
смотри яже например Это не слышал
never heard that they talked about money about these
никогда что об деньгах о этих
and I hear it from you for the first time
разговаривали и от тебя первый раз
You may know here in Damascus there is an
слышу Ты может знаешь вот в дамаске есть
Amiya dska mosque a
Амия дска мечеть
mosque in Damascus mosque Amiya mosque Amid
мечеть в дамаске мечеть Амия мечеть
so here when Sheikh ibn
амидом так вот э когда там был Шейх ибн
Nassurdin from the greatest sheikhs of the East was there
нассурдин из величайших шейхов Востока
he spoke about God he spoke about the power of
он говорил о Боге он говорил о власти
his she he spoke about money and distributed
своё ше он говорил о деньгах и раздавал
money to his subjects and he spoke about
деньги своим подданным и он говорил о
women he had a good grief
женщинах у него был хороший горем
good
хороший
grief And what are you lips your  touch what with your
горем А что ты губы свои трогаешь что ты
fingers guy lips touch lips
пальцами парень губы трогаешь губы
touch me sore because of this it hurts
трогаешь ме болячка из-за этого болит у
me sore Because you fingers
меня так болячка Потому что ты пальцы
lips like a [ __ ] you can't put your fingers in your mouth
губы как су нельзя пальцы себе в рот
because there will be sores You first with
ложи потому что болячки будут Ты сначала
this room snake this testosterone souls and
этим рум змея этого тестостерон души а
then finger yourself lip lip
потом палец себе губа губа Это вообще
What kind of Muslim is this burning his mouth his forehead lobe bra
что за мусульманин палит рот себе лобе
Look you're a Muslim brother
ло бра Смотри ты же мусульманин брат Ты
Why are you putting your finger to your lips
зачем палец губам подносишь
Why are you calling your lip names calling your lip you're
Зачем Ты обзываешь губу обзываешь губу
talking to a man calling your lip
ты говоришь с мужчиной обзываешь губа
Ob
Обь
you do that
ты так делае
once I looked at first I thought It was an
раз я смотрел я сначала думать Это
accident then I look you licked your finger then your
случайность потом смотрю ты то палец то
lip everything again licked again
губу всё снова облизал снова
how I peeled off I just bite it
облизал как я облез Я просто её кусаю
Why are you biting your lips and
Зачем ты покусывает свои губы и
moisturizing
увлажняет
them What's the difference I don't do that there's
их А какая разница я так делаю не делаю
nothing there Where have you seen a
нету же там ничего Где ты видел чтобы
man moisten his lips or pinch
мужчина увлаж свои губы или посываю
I don't know on purpose or not on purpose
Я не знаю специально или не специально
But it's
Но это
strange you're definitely a man a
странно ты точно мужчина
man or you
мужчина или ты
loaded this
это загрузили
baby will go souls now  testosterone
малыша пойдёт души сечас тестостерон
Nago
Наго
snake subscribe to my and
змея подпишись на мий и
I don't know why it's for you why else
Я не знаю для чого це тоб для чого ще
you can watch it on my face But for
тоб там дивитись на оцей фейс Але для
you it's one two or three clicks But you
тебе це один два або три клика Але ти
try me and I will be a kti va in me there are a
тримае мене и я буду кти ва в мене там
bunch of fouls and I will be in a great mood
Купа фолов и в мене буде класний настр
to make new ones spin a video letter on y
щоб робити новые крути видео пись на й
Ista pok Andriy Oh
Иста пок Андрий О
so let me give you a check
так давай я тебе чека